ILGWU Local 9 Managers' Correspondence 5780/013
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Local 9 Managers' Correspondence
1929-1951
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Hyman, Louis
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU). Local 9
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/013
2.33 cubic feet
2.3 linear ft.
Correspondence.
The collection consists of the correspondence of managers Isidore Sorkin and Louis Hyman of Local 9 of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Includes correspondence with several departments of the Cloak Joint Board and the office of the President of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.
5490730
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, September 26, 2008
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 02, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Biographical / Historical
General managers of Local 9 included Isidore Sorkin and Louis Hyman. Isidore Sorkin was manager of Local 9 from 1925 to 1942.
Born in Russia, Louis Hyman (1884-1963) emigrated to England in 1903 before settling down in the United States in 1911. Within the ILGWU, Hyman served as business agent and executive board member of Local 9, director of the Union Health Center, and executive board member of the New York Joint Board. Hyman left the ILGWU for a time (roughly from 1925 to 1939) during which he served as president of the Needle Trades Workers Industrial Union. In 1942, he defeated Isidore Sorkin to become manager of Local 9.
Biographical / Historical
Local 9 of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), also known as the Cloak and Suit Finishers Union, was chartered in 1903 and based in New York City.
Scope and Contents
The collection is mainly composed of correspondence to the Joint Board, the ILGWU, and other organizations. Early correspondence is often from manager Isidore Sorkin (1925-1942), while later correspondence is from manager Louis Hyman (1942-). As a member of the Joint Board of the Cloak, Suit, Skirt and Reefer Makers' Union, Local 9 corresponded with the Joint Board regarding meetings, often for the Local manager meetings, as well as committees, agreements, price settlements, claims and complaints against firms. Local 9 and its members were part of the Retirement Fund of the Coat and Suit Industry in the New York Metropolitan area and there are letters regarding benefits. Additionally, there is correspondence with George Price (Director) and Leo Price (Assistant Director) of the Union Health Center concerning patients who were members of Local 9 discussing examinations in the clinic and work permits in shops.
Files labeled "President's Office" refer to documents that mainly originated from the office of ILGWU president David Dubinsky. Much is general letters and memos that went out to all the local managers and Joint Board within the union. There is also much correspondence addressed to Local 9 manager Louis Hyman.
Organizations represented in the collection include ICOR, which refers to the Association for Jewish Colonization in the Soviet Union Inc., of which Local 9 manager Hyman was a National Executive member. And manufacturers' organizations and associations (which represented the garment firms) appearing include the Industrial Council of Cloak, Suit, and Skirt Manufacturers, Inc., and the Merchants Ladies Garment Association.
Finally, there is material of an administrative nature for Local 9 such as an accounting ledger detailing assets and investments, fees and various expenses.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780/017: ILGWU Local 9 Executive Board and Grievance Committee Minutes 5780/017 P: ILGWU Local 9 Executive Board and Grievance Committee Photographs
Women's clothing industry -- United States; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Clothing workers -- United States; Industrial relations -- United States; Sorkin, Isidore; Hyman, Louis; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 9 (New York, N.Y.)
5490730
- A, 1936-1939 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Incl. form letters from American Youth Congress, 1937.
- American Cloak and Suit Mfrs. Assoc., 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- American Labor Party, 1936-1939 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Corres. on campaigns in New York State, incl. Isidore Nagler for Borough President, Bronx County, 1937.
- B, 1939-1949 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- C, 1937-1948 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Cloak Jt. Bd. (N.Y.), 1945-1949 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Incl. correspondence., reports, proposals for negotiations; form letters.
- Cloak Jt. Bd. (N.Y.), 1942-1944 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Cloak Jt. Bd. (N.Y.), 1939-1941 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Incl. collective agreement between Union & Brooklyn Cloak & Suit Truckers Assoc., 1939.
- Cloak Jt. Bd., 1938 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Cloak Jt. Bd., 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Cloak Jt. Bd., Adjustment Dept., 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Cloak Jt. Bd., Ashbes, Morris J Sec-Treas., 1933-1934 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Incl. correspondence. w. B. Cooper, Mgr. Local 9 on expulsion of members Bernstein & Greenberg from Jt. Bd., 1933.
- Cloak Jt. Bd., Brooklyn Office, 1937-1949 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Corres. w. Anthony Cottone, Manager.
- Cloak Jt. Bd., Brooklyn Office, 1938-1946 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Reports.
- Cloak Jt. Bd., Merchants American Dept. Complaints, A-K. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Cloak Jt. Bd., Merchants American Dept. Complaints, L-Z. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Cloak Jt. Bd., Merchants American Dept., 1936-1939 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Complaints (reverse chronological order).
- Cloak Jt. Bd., Merchants American Dept., 1941-1946 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Reports by H. Slutsky, Manager.
- Cloak Jt. Bd., Organization and Patrol Dept., 1941-1946 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  March 1941-1949. Corres. w. Philip Herman, Manager; reports.
- Cloak Jt. Bd., Organization and Patrol Dept., 1934-1941 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  1934-February 1941. Incl. correspondence. w. Joseph Boruchowitz, A.S. Miller, and I. Stenzor.
- Education Dept., 1935-1948 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Letters from Fannia M. Conn, correspondence. w. Mark Starr, leaflets & pamphlets.
- Executive Board Cases., 1936-1944 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Tillie Kessler case, 1936; Ben Kenigsberg case, 1943; Mike Goldofsky vs. Morris Appelbaum, 1943-1944.
- F, 1937-1939 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Incl. letters of Friends of Abraham Lincoln Brigade, 1937.
- Furriers Joint Council of New York., 1939 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Incl. complaint from Irving Potash, Manager, that cloak firms are purchasing fur garments from non-Union shops & Contractors, 1939.
- G-H, 1937-1949 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- I, 1937-1949 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  Incl. ICOR, 1937.
- Industrial Council of Cloak, Suit and Skirt Mfrs., Inc., 1936-1948 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  Incl. letters from Samuel Klein, Executive Director.
- Infants and Children's Coat Assoc., 1938-1949 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- J, 1937-1949 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- L, 1937-1948 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Labor Bureau, New York Coat and Suit Industry, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  Report, Memorandum for associations in opposition to wage adjustment.
- Locals, 1936-1948 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  Arranged numerically by local.
- M, 1937-1949 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Merchants Ladies Garment Association, 1936-1939 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- P, 1937-1948 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- President's Office, 1939-1949 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  Corres. w. D.D., form letters.
- President's Office, 1941-1942 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- President's Office, 1939-1940 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- President's Office, 1937-1938 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- President's Office, 1933-1936 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- R, 1937-1949 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Retirement Fund of Coat and Suit Industry, 1944-1949 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  Corres. w. Herbert Zame, Manager, on benefits, financial reports.
- S, 1937-1949 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Shop Meetings, notices, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- T-U, 1937-1948 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Umhey, Frederick F., 1934-1949 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Union Health Center, 1929-1949 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  Corres. w. George M. Price, Director.
- V-Z, 1937-1948 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  Incl. Workmen's Circle.
- Accounting ledger, 1949-1951 (Box 5, Folder 1)